GPT 5.5 is already smarter than most of us, surely smarter than me.
But the only thing that makes me a better engineer or is that I have more context.
You can literally do anything.
It's like fascinating to build with Codex every day.
Oh, no. Oh!
Thank you so much for coming.
Super excited to be in London with all of you.
I literally had the idea on Sunday night in SF.
I was laying down in bed I think at 11 p.m. my time.
I thought, wait, I'm flying to London tomorrow.
I wonder if I could do more with developers and test it.
And by the time I woke up, I saw a Luma page up.
And then I boarded my flight, which had no Wi-Fi,
and by the time I landed, we had like we were at like 600 plus sign ups already.
It was insane.
So I guess this is the one.
Maybe that's like too close. Oh, the hand mic.
Okay, let's do the hand mic.
It's going to be harder with the demos, but it's going to be fine.
Oh yeah. It's fine. Cool.
So yeah, super excited to be here.
It's funny on the way here with VB and Jimmy, I was asking them
like, wait, what should we present as content?
And VB was like, no slides, just vibes.
So I was like, all right,
we're just gonna we're just going to open up the Codex app.
Well, maybe for all of you that that use the CLI still.
I mean obviously we love the CLI.
We started there, the CLI open source.
That's also where a lot of the harness for Codex is.
And it's also open source. We care a lot about that.
And effectively the app is just a new interface right to access this.
But the reason why we built it is because we saw so many developers
having screens working like this.
It's like you start with two agents and then you end up
like Peter Steinberger, who had like 15 in parallel to build OpenClaw.
And then you start like kind of losing track of like,
which agent is asking for my attention for what?
And in which server is running everywhere.
And we let those to run.
So that's what we'll do. Codex app. Right.
And the idea is to have a very elegant and simple interface for you
to have all your projects in one place, and also an interface
that kind of morphs itself depending on what you need.
And you've you've probably seen us do a lot more of that in the past few weeks.
And so first capability, for instance, that's kind of cool.
Like just like issued a prompt to say like, hey, like,
can you make an illustration for tonight and boom, right away,
like we have like the beautiful image into if you have not tried,
imagine it's pretty outstanding now because like remember like a year ago,
most of the imagine that you could generate would have typos in text.
Now it's it's extremely, extremely challenging to find one typo
even like asking to generate a book like all of the local
characters would be correct.
So it's pretty mind blowing.
But what's also interesting is the idea that you can really delegate agentically
and have like a better control command center, almost like, for instance,
like this project wanderlust.
I have not really worked on it for a while,
so I can just say upgrade all of the dependencies, Next.js
and all of the node modules and make sure there's no like security issues in there,
just like fire that off and it might take ten, 20,
30 minutes, but I don't really mind because I'll check back on that later.
So that's really the idea of like delegating agentically.
Maybe I'll highlight a few things that are new is of like a couple of weeks ago.
One thing that's very new in the spirit of like Codex,
for almost everything, as we called it, is like this like catalog of plugins.
We started with just a dozen of them.
Now there's more like 120 plugins in there and we keep adding more every week.
We want to make sure Codex has all the context to all of all of the tools we use.
Right?
Like GPT 5.5 is already smarter than most of us, surely smarter than me.
But the only thing that makes me a better engineer or a better employee
is that I have more context.
And so if you give all of these context to GPT 5.5,
it can really become a teammate that helps you.
So for instance, like Gmail, linear, whatever, your bug tracker
can be like slack to stay on top of everything.
And we'll show some of these in action here.
So meanwhile we see here, for instance, that like it's cranking still,
it's like finding all of the builds and things to update.
One thing that I really want to highlight, and I know it's not in Europe just yet,
but we're very excited about it and we'll do our best
to bring it to your very, very soon.
It's computer use, and if you have not seen it in action,
you're actually missing out, which is what I wanted to show it to you tonight,
because it's unlike every implementation of computer use that exists out there.
Like anyone that has talked about
computer use has shown it in a way where like you ask an agent to do a thing
on your computer, but all of a sudden you can't
you can't use your computer anymore because then your agent
is clicking around and doing things.
And so I really want to show you like a little bit of how this one works.
So easier.
For instance, I have this app that been building for us
and I simply tell Codex, build and run the app, right?
But what if I actually want to show the app?
I can basically say, can you open the simulator
and click from the first to the third tab in the navigation?
So I could send this prompt.
I'll show it to you before here because it's something interesting.
Obviously if I send this prompt code. Excellent.
But like here, if you add mention, any app on your computer
becomes available to Codex.
So it's not just the plugins like Gmail, it's also like the app on your computer.
So I can say like, hey, can you open this app and click through?
So if I send this task, what's interesting is that
it would allow me to like like I should allow like could control it.
I just did already.
But now if you take a look at this, it's now clicking
through the things and it has its own cursor.
It's not my cursor, I'm still using it.
So it's really, really cool.
And to show you maybe how you can combine
these things for some ideas, let me find a new idea.
Maybe I'll send the first prompt here.
I don't know how long it will take, but let's say can you take a look at my email?
And I must have received an email
from VB about the Codex community event.
Can you pull the list of attendees and pick
three out of them that were accepted to come tonight?
Literally have no idea if it works, I'm just going to try.
So it's probably going to try to understand that my email must be Gmail.
Connect to the plugins and everything we'll give it,
we'll give it a few seconds. We'll come back to it.
It's it's looking through my my Gmail.
So we'll give it a second.
Another thing I wanted to show you is the inner browser.
Right. Imagine you're building web apps.
Well, you know, often you go back and forth.
And in the past we all use Chrome dev tools to do things to adjust the CSS
and everything, which was great at the time.
But now that we're building with agents, we can do so much more.
And so the really cool thing about having an inner browser, let's say, for this
fitness app I'm working on, is that not only can I visualize in real time,
I can also comment to give context to the agent super instantly.
I can say, hey, change this with the date of today, boom!
And then I'll just find that off, go do it, and then I can keep on like
highlighting things and commenting.
And so maybe I can say like actually make this bigger,
make this smaller, make it an animation over here.
And sure enough, it's
going to take like a few seconds to figure out the right react component here.
I actually have the app maybe translated, so it's probably going to try
to also figure out where to put this.
It doesn't want our code. You want to do the right thing.
So that's Codex being relentless. So it's going to do it.
But yeah really cool idea to have like this in-app browser that you can use.
And of course you can maximize it.
You can really be in the flow right there.
So really, really convenient.
Meanwhile, if we take a look at how I see the date of today
just appeared perfect, let's take a look at these attendees.
It sounds like we have those three attendees that were selected right there.
So here I can also say.
Can you use Chrome
to open three new tabs to pull up the LinkedIn profiles?
And so
here once again I could fire up that that task.
But here you can see that Chrome.
Oh interesting.
Oh yeah. This is for the Chrome extension.
That's fine.
And it should be able to like actually open and navigate Chrome
and do things like this.
So it's so it's pretty cool.
So it's going to try to use the Chrome plugin.
So I'm going to do that. Great.
I didn't have it installed on this demo laptop.
Great.
Another thing I could also say for instance is like to show you
one last thing, to have another thing going on in the meantime.
So see, it's opening now like chrome and controlling chrome over here.
But maybe for another.
For another example of how you can use computer use here.
For instance, I had on slack a message from my teammates the other day
saying that like,
oh, for this Vercel incident, we should probably rotate the keys of the secrets.
So I can probably say like, hey, can you open the reminders app
and like put the reminder for me, I'll do that tonight.
And it's like, okay, I'm going to use computer use.
And once again it's going to open up by itself, most likely the reminders app.
And it's going to be looking at reminders.
And sure enough, the reminders app is going to navigate the reminder app.
And like we see the cursor moving, it's going to rotate the keys.
And you can have as many of these things as you want.
Like it's really happening in the background.
I can still use my computer. So really, really cool.
We want to use we want to bring computer use to Europe as soon as we possibly can,
because this is very cool.
And when you start having all of the plugins connecting
to all of your contexts, you start having all of your skills
that define the way you write code at your company.
And then when you start
having computer use for everything else to navigate your apps, you literally
have every possible context now available to Codex in the cloud and locally.
So that's really, really convenient to have your agents being
so much more effective.
So yeah, great.
Now maybe two, 2 or 3 more things that I want to highlight.
One thing that is very,
very interesting for all of you fullstack engineers and frontend developers.
We know that like for a while, like GPT models were not the best at designing.
That's still something we're pushing hard on and we're very, very confident
the next one will will nail this.
But in the meantime, it's kind of always like almost fixed already.
Because if you I don't know if you've seen this, this flow,
but when you use plugins, there's one plugin that we built called the Build Web
Apps plugin.
And that one in particular has the ability to create designs using Imogen.
And you can end up with like let's say with these two front I built,
you can have something that's like beautifully designed with Imogen.
And then you just tell Codex, go implement that design, and then you have this
like almost flawless implementation of a design
that has been actually something you saw and reviewed as opposed to
like vibe coding something in the blind
where you're not really sure what the design will look like.
So that's really, really convenient.
It's like image gen 2.0 to GPT 5.5 to implement.
The other thing I wanted to show you as well
is using Imogen for creating games and assets.
Like I just simply like sent a prompt to say, hey, I want to create
a game called like initially Sits Your Crossing.
And then I renamed it Codex Crossing.
But I said I wanted something
inspired by Animal Crossing, but with great assets for developers.
And sure enough, it's like liquid expats.
It's like Germany generated all of these assets right there.
And then you can start like interacting with whoops,
I just tell Codex, can you run the server again?
You know, even easier to talk to Codex than to do it myself.
But you can really see like the,
the quality of these assets, the consistency, if you want to create
sprites for games and everything, it's really, really cool.
So that's like GPT image and you really have it by default
when you just ask Codex to generate images.
Sure. I'll start the server again.
There you go. And it should it should be back.
Yeah.
So if you. Yeah.
What VB reminded me is
like when you ask Codex
to generate images that's already included in your subscription.
So there's no separate charges for like an API endpoint of sorts.
So yeah.
So you can really like generate game
and let the creativity flow with all of these assets.
And then let's see what else can I do before we go on to take questions.
Maybe one fun thing is that, like, you can really imagine having Codex
as an app where you're going to start talking to it
and building and also the ability to review things.
So for instance, I just sent this prompt that said like, can you just generate
a default like Space Invaders game that I can just start playing with?
But what's interesting is like here, I can now keep on commenting
while I'm playing the game.
So I don't know if any of you have any ideas,
but we can just iterate on this game together.
What should we do with it?
What do you want?
Oh, a health bar.
Okay, let's add a health bar
for for my character.
Great.
Let's let's cue that.
Let's make it goblin themed.
The bad guys are orange crabs.
Okay. So.
Great one.
So, like,
so I'm just.
Vibing over here. We'll see what happens.
But in this case I'm actually using Codex Spark, which is
the model that runs on Cerebras chips.
So it's not as smart as like 5.5
because it's a smaller model, but it's usually responding faster.
So let's see, it's still working on this thing okay.
Let's take a look. Refresh okay.
So it's goblin theme now. Cool.
All right I'm going to do another one which is can
you wire up wireless Xbox controller to it.
So I always have an X box controller hanging around.
So hopefully in a few minutes we'll see that.
I guess it's as it's working as it worked on the health bar.
I guess that's. They're. Not sure.
I think.
I think that is.
Yeah, that's the hard part.
It did it.
Yeah. It's pretty cool. Okay.
And then the goblins okay, cool.
It's now like,
I guess I'm going out of the context window using using this model.
Maybe I should go back to this thing while you're up an X-Box controller.
It's a wireless one. And then.
Yeah, in a few seconds
we'll have a wireless controller bound to it, which is pretty cool.
I like it, I called it Goblin Guard.
So let's see anything else that I forgot VB that I should mention?
Oh yeah, maybe one thing that's interesting actually.
Really?
Like, of course all of you are like developers, like we are.
But the thing that's like very exciting by Codex, being able
to tap into all of your contacts and all of your
and all of your work is like the amount of things you can now do
that are outside of the software realm,
like here, for instance, I was like trying to send this prompt
where I'm like trying to put together a presentation in Google Drive
about like sales of properties in San Francisco by using a data
from a spreadsheet that I downloaded.
And I'm like, okay,
go ahead and do the thing, make a deck, and also use imagine and everything.
That's what it came up with in Zero Shot.
Like you basically have like
an entire deck pulling from the data customized from using.
And so really the possibilities are endless.
And then I'm going to add the three of you here on LinkedIn.
Meanwhile,
while the game is being finished,
can I actually play this with an X box controller?
Let's take a look at this.
I think the hardest part is always to connect the controller.
And then the the actual part of implementing it is oh there you go.
I can finally play. I didn't even have anything to say.
I basically just said I wanted to play it with an X box controller.
And here I am finding the goblets.
I can even.
Yeah, it's pretty cool.
You can literally do anything.
It's like fascinating to build with Codex every day.
You want a picture of me, like with the with the with the goblins.
Is that what you wanted?
The table, what they want.
There you go.
And maybe last but not least, before we open it up for Q&A.
Right. I think I'll just tell Codex to.
I have not quite enough swag, but I have one leftover keychain
from the Super Bowl gift,
so maybe I can pick one of you with Codex to actually have it.
So I'll say, hey, I have one leftover swag item from the Super Bowl ad.
Could you pick
randomly one of the attendees from that list that is present tonight?
And then we'll see
what what Codex decides to to do?
The suspense is intense.
Meanwhile.
Oh, it is even looking at the checked in at timestamp.
Well, we have em, who apparently is the winner of this.
Little keychain.
Do you recognize yourself?
Yes. Great.
There you have it.
The designation,
Oh, no. Oh!